<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Announcements on Devies Tech Culture Business Blog</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/tags/announcements/</link><description>Recent content in Announcements on Devies Tech Culture Business Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 10:08:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/tags/announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing Workflow Timer</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-workflow-timer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 10:08:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-workflow-timer/</guid><description>Workflow-timer is a Github action that measures the duration of the workflow and compares it to historical runs.
The purpose of this action is to make the developer aware of when feedbacks loops get longer. Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you are running unit tests as part of your current workflow. If merging your changes (your PR) would increase the time it takes to run the unit tests by 50%, your changes probably have unwanted side effects.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Frontman</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-frontman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 10:08:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-frontman/</guid><description>Frontman is a very light-weight NGINX reverse proxy that is deployed using Docker. Its purpose is to act as the entry point to your server. It will redirect incoming traffic to one out of many Docker-based applications running on the same server, based on the hostname in the incoming request.
The rationale behind this is that it enables you to host as many services as you want on the same server, while still only keeping ports 80 and 443 open to the outside world.</description></item></channel></rss>