<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech Culture Busines Blog on Devies Tech Culture Business Blog</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Tech Culture Busines Blog on Devies Tech Culture Business Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Xcode 14 &amp; SPM: Deployment Pipeline in Azure</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/xcode-14-manual-signing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/xcode-14-manual-signing/</guid><description>tl;dr
Background Continuous Deployment (CD) pipelines are great tools to automate the deployment process of a software. Their main objective is to minimise human error and maintain a consistent process for how the software is released.
For Xcode projects this becomes a time critical process once the project has to be built for different configurations and/or environments. Since every configuration might require a different signing method, or even different deployment platform.</description></item><item><title>Learnings From The Pragmatic Programmer</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/learnings-from-pragmatic-programmer-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 12:44:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/learnings-from-pragmatic-programmer-1/</guid><description>At Devies we run a book club where we on a weekly basis discuss topics from a book that we are reading in a common pace. Recently we finished The Pragmatic Programmer, 20th Anniversary Edition. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll share learnings around some of the topics we have discussed.
Tracer Bullets vs Prototypes Two of the topics discussed in the book are tracer bullets and prototypes. The concepts are similar but addresses different problems.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Libraries in Your Android Project: A Quick and Easy Guide</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/upgrading-libraries-in-your-android-project-a-quick-and-easy-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:05:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/upgrading-libraries-in-your-android-project-a-quick-and-easy-guide/</guid><description>Hey fellow developers! Upgrading libraries in your gradle file for an Android project is a crucial part of keeping your project up to date and running smoothly. However, it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to encounter errors or deprecated code after upgrading a library. If this happens to you, don&amp;rsquo;t panic! There are a few steps you can take to fix the issues and get your project back on track.
Understanding the Role of Gradle Files In an Android project, there are two main gradle build files that you might need to work with: the &amp;ldquo;build.</description></item><item><title>Take Advantage of the Tools in the Toolbox</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/learn-the-tools-in-the-toolbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 08:25:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/learn-the-tools-in-the-toolbox/</guid><description>Last week I ended up spending more time than I expected on debugging. I spent most of the time figuring out why a library did not accept my freshly generated RSA private key. I was supposed to provide the RSA private key as an environment variable RSA_PRIVATE_KEY. I wanted to store the RSA private key in a file private-key.pem so my first attempt became RSA_PRIVATE_KEY=\&amp;quot;$(cat private-key.pem)\&amp;quot; docker-compose up -d, which failed due to decoding issues by the library.</description></item><item><title>How Xcode Bamboozled Me</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/how-xcode-bamboozled-me/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 16:49:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/how-xcode-bamboozled-me/</guid><description>A common dilemma within the field of software development is traversing too deep within documentation to discover the solution to a bug. This struggle can be represented and reflected in many aspects of life, however as developers we encounter this dilemma more often than not. This post is about how I fell into this dilemma and got bamboozled by Apple&amp;rsquo;s integrated development environment, Xcode.
It&amp;rsquo;s ten o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning and I&amp;rsquo;ve just configured and bumped the dependencies for my client&amp;rsquo;s android application which they hadn&amp;rsquo;t touched for over two years.</description></item><item><title>Why You Should Keep a Developer Diary</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/why-you-should-keep-a-developer-diary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 14:45:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/why-you-should-keep-a-developer-diary/</guid><description>Every software developer should keep a diary.
Personally I&amp;rsquo;ve kept one for about a year now, and I&amp;rsquo;m very content. During some periods I haven&amp;rsquo;t bothered, and that&amp;rsquo;s OK. I can always write a new entry tomorrow, or next week.
The diary can cover a lot of different aspects from your daily work. Below are some examples.
Things you&amp;rsquo;ve learned Accomplishments that you&amp;rsquo;re proud of Thoughts on dynamics within your team Sketches of ideas Reasoning behind technical decisions Solutions to problems that you&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with I think the greatest benefit of writing a diary is that you give yourself time to reflect on your daily work.</description></item><item><title>Zod</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/zod-data-verification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 14:02:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/zod-data-verification/</guid><description>tl;dr
TypeScript is already a great upgrade from JavaScript if you like types and want to ensure type-safety in your code base. Zod aids that goal by making sure that incoming data satisfies the purpose it is about to fulfill, among other features of course.
Zod is a TypeScript-first schema declaration and validation library with lots of features that I have yet to use. However, the basics are very handy and simple to get started with!</description></item><item><title>Integration Test Api in .Net Using Reflection</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/integration-test-api-controller-in-.net-using-reflection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 09:07:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/integration-test-api-controller-in-.net-using-reflection/</guid><description>There are a few different approaches to testing in the spectrum between simple unit tests and complete E2E tests. If I had to choose one approach to prioritize I would pick integration tests.
The key reasons are:
Tests a flow of multiple functions, in contrast with unit tests where only a single function is tested Self contained i.e. the test has no external dependencies on a deployed environment etc. Makes logical sense to test a complete function in a REST api, a single Lambda in AWS or an Azure function The problem In my case the goal was to setup a test suite for a .</description></item><item><title>Mitigating Primitive Obsession in ASP.NET Web Api</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/mitigating-primitive-obsession-in-asp.net-web-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 15:43:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/mitigating-primitive-obsession-in-asp.net-web-api/</guid><description>One of the projects we work with at Devies is related to the dental domain. In that project we use the dental notation (ISO 3950) to refer to teeth. Every tooth have an unique identifier that consist of two characters. The first character represent a quadrant (one of four areas in the mouth). The second character is an identifier that refers to one of the eight teeth in that area.</description></item><item><title>Conventional Commits and Generating Changelogs</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/conventional-commits-and-generating-changelogs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 16:43:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/conventional-commits-and-generating-changelogs/</guid><description>Documentation, while in many cases important, might not be the first thing you as a developer want to spend time on doing. Something you might do like as a developer is to spend a lot of time automating simple but tedious tasks in order to never have to do it manually again! With documentation being a particularly important part in our project we were extra keen on finding as many ways of automating documentation as possible.</description></item><item><title>.NET 6 Surprises</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/.net-6-surprises/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 09:15:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/.net-6-surprises/</guid><description>A few weeks ago, we upgraded one of our projects from .NET 5 to .NET 6, since .NET 5 was nearing end of support. In this process, we ran into a few hurdles. This post will go through a few of them that were a bit unexpected, and why we ran into them.
AccessTokenValidation deprecated This isn&amp;rsquo;t completely related to .NET 6 in itself, but we ran into the issue during the upgrade.</description></item><item><title>The kubectl wait Command</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/kubectl-wait-command/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 10:48:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/kubectl-wait-command/</guid><description>Last week, while writing end-to-end tests for our Kubernetes application, we discovered a useful Kubernetes command. Namely, the kubectl wait command. We managed to stabilize our test using this command, and we will explain how we did it in this post.
We have written our end-to-end tests in bash, and they deploy and manage different Kubernetes resources. Bash scripts execute commands sequentially, waiting for the first to finish before executing the next one.</description></item><item><title>Trick your local web server using the Host header</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/trick-local-web-server-using-host-header/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 14:56:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/trick-local-web-server-using-host-header/</guid><description>TLDR: If you need to &amp;ldquo;trick&amp;rdquo; a local web server that you&amp;rsquo;re making requests to a certain domain, but do not want (or have permissions) to modify /etc/hosts - Set the intended domain in the Host request header instead.
We are currently working on a project where we have an nginx instance that is redirecting traffic for many different domains. In our case, the nginx is an ingress controller in a kubernetes cluster, but you might use a similar approach if you&amp;rsquo;re hosting multiple websites on the same webserver.</description></item><item><title>We Got Cached 😱</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/we-got-cached/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 13:29:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/we-got-cached/</guid><description>For the past couple of weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a React app from scratch. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ve added pipelines in Azure as an attempt to achieve MAXIMUM EFFICIENCY when it comes to deployment and integration. So there we are. It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely morning. The sun is shining, the coffee is warm, and we&amp;rsquo;re ready to drop some lines of code! 😎
Last week we built and deployed a version of our React app that had a slightly faulty CSS attribute that made the header of the app take up the whole screen.</description></item><item><title>Why you should add a cypress test to your CI/CD pipeline</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/why-you-should-add-a-cypress-test-to-your-ci-cd-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:29:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/why-you-should-add-a-cypress-test-to-your-ci-cd-pipeline/</guid><description>Cypress is a framework for testing web applications, primarily used for end-to-end testing. In an end-to-end test you test your application as a whole just as a real user would, by interacting with GUI components, without any mocked components. The goal of this post is to convince you to add a single simple cypress test to your CI/CD pipeline.
In end-to-end tests with cypress you can test a lot of aspects of your application with very little test code.</description></item><item><title>Better Terminal Experience for Git and Kubernetes</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/a-tip-for-improving-the-terminal-experience-when-working-with-git-and-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 21:04:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/a-tip-for-improving-the-terminal-experience-when-working-with-git-and-kubernetes/</guid><description>When working on a project that uses git, it is essential to checkout the correct branch. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to realize after a few hours of work that you worked on the wrong branch and have a few messy merges and rebases in front of you. Of course, the easiest way to show the current branch is to run git status but that requires an action from you, Instead, I recommend you to include the git branch as part of your prompt string.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Workflow Timer</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-workflow-timer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 10:08:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-workflow-timer/</guid><description>Workflow-timer is a Github action that measures the duration of the workflow and compares it to historical runs.
The purpose of this action is to make the developer aware of when feedbacks loops get longer. Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you are running unit tests as part of your current workflow. If merging your changes (your PR) would increase the time it takes to run the unit tests by 50%, your changes probably have unwanted side effects.</description></item><item><title>Using managed identities and role based access control is great!</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/managed-identities-and-rbac-is-great/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:15:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/managed-identities-and-rbac-is-great/</guid><description>In a project I work with we use Azure App Service for hosting an ASP.NET application. All external configuration used by the application is stored in an Azure App Configuration store. I recently updated how the application authenticates toward the App Configuration store and think it worked out pretty well.
Prior to the change we used connection strings (i.e. a string containing endpoint, username and password) for authentication. The main drawback with this is that we have to manage the credentials ourselves.</description></item><item><title>Long feedback loops invite for context switching</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/2022-02-22-long-feedback-loops-invite-for-context-switching/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 10:08:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/2022-02-22-long-feedback-loops-invite-for-context-switching/</guid><description>As a backend developer, there is especially one thing that I’m jealous of when it comes to frontend development. The short feedback loop, namely, the time and effort it takes to get feedback for your changes. Enable hot or live reloading while developing, and the results of your changes will be in front of you instantly, which is super nice. This is how it should be, even when you are developing the backend, infrastructure, CI/CD, or whatever.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Frontman</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-frontman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 10:08:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-frontman/</guid><description>Frontman is a very light-weight NGINX reverse proxy that is deployed using Docker. Its purpose is to act as the entry point to your server. It will redirect incoming traffic to one out of many Docker-based applications running on the same server, based on the hostname in the incoming request.
The rationale behind this is that it enables you to host as many services as you want on the same server, while still only keeping ports 80 and 443 open to the outside world.</description></item><item><title>How I've automated the setup of my virtual server</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/automated-ec2-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 05:57:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/automated-ec2-setup/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a good way of hosting some personal projects. I wanted something relatively cheap which I could use to host multiple services. A colleague of mine have for a long time used a single virtual server (more specifically, an EC2 instance in AWS) where he runs multiple services inside docker containers. To enable access to each individual service, there&amp;rsquo;s a NGINX reverse proxy that forwards traffic to services.</description></item><item><title>Trying out AWS Timestream</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/aws-timestream/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 15:50:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/aws-timestream/</guid><description>AWS recently (last year) released their new server-less database focused purely on time series data, Amazon Timestream. On their product page, AWS describes the database like:
&amp;ldquo;Amazon Timestream is a fast, scalable, and serverless time series database service for IoT and operational applications that makes it easy to store and analyze trillions of events per day up to 1,000 times faster and at as little as 1/10th the cost of relational databases.</description></item><item><title>Minimize Java Lambda Cold Start Times</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/implementation/aws/2021/04/08/minimize-java-lambda-coldstarts.html/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 09:25:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/implementation/aws/2021/04/08/minimize-java-lambda-coldstarts.html/</guid><description>If you have ever run Java inside a lambda function on AWS, you will have noticed the quite significant cold start times that comes with spinning up the JVM environment. In this post, I will discuss some different tricks you can use to minimize these cold start times.
The problem with cold starts arises when there are no &amp;ldquo;warm&amp;rdquo; lambda available to handle an incoming request, which usually happens whenever an endpoint experiences a large and sudden spike in traffic.</description></item><item><title>Migrating data between DynamoDB tables</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/2021-03-30-dynamodb-migrations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/2021-03-30-dynamodb-migrations/</guid><description>When setting up a new DynamoDB table, an important decision is to decide what primary key to use. However, it’s not uncommon to not have the full picture up front and therefore it could be hard to make the right decision beforehand. While the official AWS documentation states that “you shouldn’t start designing your schema for DynamoDB until you know the questions it will need to answer”, you often need to experiment to be able to discover what those questions are.</description></item><item><title>Analytics without third-party tools</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/2020-09-01-analytics-poc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/2020-09-01-analytics-poc/</guid><description>Finding out how much traffic your site has and how your users interact with it is always crucial. Such information will enable you to scale your backend properly, fine-tune the user experience and weed out unused features. Some even go so far as claiming that data is the &amp;ldquo;gold of our time&amp;rdquo;. Regardless of the truth of that claim, few can dispute the usefulness of user analytics data.
The go-to solution for most developers is to use Google Analytics (in fact used by 55% of all websites) or some other third party framework.</description></item></channel></rss>