<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CI on Devies blog</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/tags/ci/</link><description>Recent content in CI on Devies blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 13:29:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/tags/ci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>We Got Cached 😱</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/we-got-cached/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 13:29:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/we-got-cached/</guid><description>For the past couple of weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a React app from scratch. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ve added pipelines in Azure as an attempt to achieve MAXIMUM EFFICIENCY when it comes to deployment and integration. So there we are. It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely morning. The sun is shining, the coffee is warm, and we&amp;rsquo;re ready to drop some lines of code! 😎
Last week we built and deployed a version of our React app that had a slightly faulty CSS attributes that made the header of the app take up the whole screen.</description></item><item><title>Why you should add a cypress test to your CI/CD pipeline</title><link>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/why-you-should-add-a-cypress-test-to-your-ci-cd-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:29:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://deviesdevelopment.github.io/blog/posts/why-you-should-add-a-cypress-test-to-your-ci-cd-pipeline/</guid><description>Cypress is a framework for testing web applications, primarily used for end-to-end testing. In an end-to-end test you test your application as a whole just as a real user would, by interacting with GUI components, without any mocked components. The goal of this post is to convince you to add a single simple cypress test to your CI/CD pipeline.
In end-to-end tests with cypress you can test a lot of aspects of your application with very little test code.</description></item></channel></rss>